been recently receiving a lot of
questions about who i am
and so i thought i would take the
opportunity to briefly reintroduce
myself
my name is paola and i live in
northeastern washington state
in okanogan county i moved here a couple
of years ago
and take a lot of inspiration from the
natural area for
my work as an artist not only do i love
to paint
and do crafting projects inspired by
nature but
i love to make videos that help
highlight the beauty
of the natural landscape in this area so
that we can continue to preserve it for
the future
i will mention more on that at the end
of this video
bye
right now i am in the midst of winter
which is not always an easy time
and like clockwork two weeks into
february when the temperatures are at
their lowest
i suddenly find myself looking forward
to spring
i deeply enjoy the winter and know how
vital it is for the function of our
worlds and
yet i am human and may grumble now and
then about the cold
one way that i cope is taking deep
breaths and imagining a time of warmth
and color that is just around the corner
[Music]
the reason that i always become
impatient in february is because my
absolute favorite time of year is
approaching
i love spring with all my heart and soul
it is when i feel most alive and most
creative as an artist
i spend much of my time outdoors and
when summer comes i find myself ever
attracted to the mountains
seeking higher ground where spring is
still at its height
and the alpine flowers are blooming i so
look forward to it and cannot wait to
share it with you
in the meantime i find that creating art
is the most effective remedy
to keep color and life in my heart when
the days seem so long
and cold
my greatest dream since i was a child
was to create a picture book
that both children and adults can enjoy
a bridge between stories for little ones
and grown-ups
since i think we have a lot more in
common than we know
i've been recently spending more and
more of my free time working on this
project
and hope someday in the future to have
it complete but these things take time
and i've had to remind myself to be
patient and keep the process of creating
meditative and meaningful
lest i hear the end result and skip the
beauty of creation
i believe that is true for many of the
goals we set for ourselves
foreign as an adult
i quickly realized it isn't always
realistic to hope that somehow you can
pursue your passion full-time
and that that isn't a bad thing for me
much of the inspiration to create
comes from having to put a high value on
my free time and see it as a gift and
opportunity to get creative
i've greatly enjoyed working a variety
of jobs while developing creative
projects on the side
what helped me was finding a job that
facilitated my creativity
for example i once worked at a bookstore
and was often inspired by my
conversations with other bibliophiles
later teaching children and sharing my
art with them
was an enormous source of creativity
while i'm planning to set aside more
time in the future to focus on my art
the journey leading there has been
incredibly beneficial to who i am
also my dreams haven't worked out
exactly as they were in my mind's eye
and i'm very grateful for that in
retrospect
things didn't just work out magically i
had to work hard at it and develop my
character and self-worth in the process
while it's often impossible to fulfill
all our desires
it's usually much easier to simply
incorporate what we love into our daily
life
and see the worth in the process of
getting to where we want to go
[Music]
do
so
for me letting go of the desire for
worldly success
opened me to begin truly enjoying art
because i did it for no one else and
instead painted what i love
and when you put love into anything the
end result
is truly beautiful not everyone will
recognize it
but you will know it's there and that is
all that matters
[Music]
of course as you've probably gained from
watching these videos
it means a lot to me to try to do my
part to help preserve the world that i
love
and so i wanted to let you know that
with your help
so far this year we've been able to
plant 200 trees
in the forests of british columbia which
are trying to be reforested at the
moment
after some heavy wildfires also
i have been able to pledge almost 200 to
the nrdc
which is an organization here in the u.s
which not only seeks to preserve wild
areas but help improve air quality
and reduce pollution in areas where we
live as well
so i wanted to say thank you since i
know this is all made possible because
of you
and your generous support and i hope
this is just the beginning
i plan to do a lot more in the future
and i will keep you updated
thank you so very much and i hope you
enjoyed the video
i will see you next week bye